一二三四
One, two, three, four.
跳个步 二二三四
And skip, two, three, four.
转个圈 三二三四
And turn, two, three, four.
我不喜欢这一段
I don't like this part.
没事宝贝 墙上找个点盯住
Well, honey, if you spot the wall,
就不会头晕了 爸秀给你看 好吗
then you won't get dizzy. Here, watch daddy, okay?
你说你要是
How cool would it be
转着转着就变身神奇女侠得有多酷
if you turned into Wonder Woman right now?
别跟我提这茬
Can't even talk about it.
是领养中心打来的
Oh, it's the adoption agency.
我的妈呀 有信吗 有戏吗
Oh, my gosh. It is?! It is?! It is?!
小卡 别总跟打了鸡血似的
Cam, you need to stop doing that.
上次他们打来不过是确认账单地址而已
Last time, they were just calling To confirm our billing address.
你好
Hello?
-是吗 -"是"什么啊
- Uh-huh. - "Uh-huh" What?
好的
Yep.
-真的吗 -什么"真的"啊
- Really? - "Really" What?
那个住在卡莱克西科的孕妇选中了我们
That--that mother from CAlexico, she picked us.
真的吗
She did?
她预产期提前 今天就要生了
She--she went into early labor. She's having the baby today.
真的吗
She is?!
我们得马上赶往卡莱克西科
We have to go to CAlexico right now.
-真的吗 -全是真话你就别做惊讶状了
- We do?! - Just assume everything I say is the truth.
好吧
Okay, yeah.
行 没问题 好的
Okay. Oh, okay, yes.
太感谢你了 好 再见
Well , thank you so much. Okay, bye.
咱今天就能带个新娃回家了
Um... we're getting a baby today.
我的亲娘耶 我的七舅老爷耶
Oh, my gosh! Oh, my gosh! We're...
等等 莉莉的表演会怎么办
Wait, wait, wait. What do we do about Lily's recital?
那啥 我们先让她坐稳了
Um... well, you know what? We'll--we'll just sit her down.
先晓之以理 再用冰棒动之以情
We'll--we'll tell her. We'll-- we'll give her a popsicle.
她能理解的
She'll be fine.
我们必须得赶过去
We have to do this.
好吧 你说得对
Okay, okay. Yeah, you're right
这样吧 我先去把旧婴儿车座找出来
Um, all right, I'm gonna go dig up the old car seat.
听着 咱们先
And listen, let's just...
深呼吸缓一缓 别急着奔走相告好吗
take a deep breath before we tell anyone, okay?
好
Yeah.
杰 曼尼 天大的喜事
Jay! Manny! Good news!
米奇和小卡今天要领养一个新宝宝了
Mitch and Cam are getting a new baby today!
真的吗 真是大好事啊
Really? That's fantastic.
是个拉丁宝宝哦
And it's latino!
国界线上那些栅栏也没起多大作用嘛
How's that giant fence working out for ya?
是克莱尔
It's Claire.
喂
Hello?
你听说了吗
Did you hear?
克莱尔 你好呀
Hey, Claire.
你们这就要开去某个加州边境小镇
You are driving to some California border town
领新宝宝了 我却才从歌洛莉亚那知道这事
to adopt a baby, and I have to hear about it from Gloria?
我就出去了两分钟
I was outside for two minutes.
人家已经忍耐到极限了
I kept it in as long as I could.
俺们家要来新宝宝了
We're having a baby!
-这是什么啊 -搞毛啊
- What the heck is that? - What?!
我们回来了
We're back.
艾丽克斯买到了最萌的毕业舞会裙
We got Alex the cutest prom dress.
给你爹开开眼
Show your dad.
这拉链怎么一路开到胯下 我不喜欢
Well, I don't like how far down that zipper goes,
但要说优点的话 它貌似挺防水的
but on the plus side, it looks water-resistant.
真不敢相信海莉不去舞会
I can't believe Haley's not going
要去的是艾丽克斯
to the prom and Alex is.
你这话什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
虽然不知说了多少遍 不过海莉你真应该去
I know I keep saying it, Haley, but you should be going.
这可是你青葱岁月里浓墨重彩的一刻
It's a major moment in a teenager's life,
你正眼睁睁看它溜走
And you're missing it.
毕业舞会最没劲
Proms are lame.
一群书呆子找借口打扮得花枝招展
It's just an excuse for dressed up dorks
以便坐加长礼车 互相乱搞罢了
to ride in limos and hump each other.
是吗 现在我倒有点不想让艾丽克斯去了
Okay. Now I don't like the idea of Alex going.
亲爱的 没事 她可是艾丽克斯啊
Sweetie, I think we're fine. It's--it's Alex.
你这话又是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是你就一宅女
It means you're a geek.
好吧 告诉你们
You know what? You know what?
我今夜没准也要放纵一把
I might just go crazy tonight
跟某人耳鬓厮磨什么的
And--and--and hook up all over him.
好吧
Okay.
你们笑个屁啊 有什么好笑的
Why are you laughing? That's not funny.
我今晚连眼镜都不会带
I'm not even gonna wear my glasses!
看来是不用操心了
I feel better now.
好了 我要去商场了
All right, I'm going to the mall.
我们得谈一谈 宝贝
Um, we need to talk, honey.
我们很担心你
We're worried about you.
自从大学把你列入候补名单以后 就音信全无
You haven't heard back from the college that wait-listed you,
而你的其他朋友都收到了回复
and all the rest of your friends have.
现在你每天都在商场里打发时间
And now you're just wasting time at the mall.
权当知会你们一声
For your information,
我的社区大学申请表格
I've already filled out and dropped off
已经填好并寄出了
my community college application.
另外呢
And plus also
我去商场是因为我有个工作面试
I'm going to the mall because I have a job interview.
-什么 -真的吗
- What? - Really?
我的指导顾问建议我给自己一年"空档"期
My guidance counselor suggested I take a gap year.
就是在高中毕业和上大学之前这段时间
You know, a year between high school and college
你可以上几门课 丰富一下生活阅历
where you take some courses, have some life experiences,
并从中汲取灵感
and get inspired.
所以这不 我就去GAP工作了
And obviously, work at the GAP.
搭建模型飞机第一步
The first step in plane building--
分门别类整理好
Organize the parts.
这边是动力装置 那边是机身
You got your power plant. You got your fuselage.
这一块是操纵界面
You got your control surfaces.
那是神马玩意
What's that?
熟食拼盘
A charcuterie.
这边是熏火腿 那边是咸猪肉
You got your prosciutto, your pancetta,
这一块是腊肠
your salami.
这就是熟食拼盘吗
That's charcuterie?
这么多年来我每次点菜都回避它
I've been avoiding that on menus for years.
起这么个破名字 谁还想要吃
They're killing themselves with that name.
他们来了 他们来了
They're here! They're here!
多谢你愿意帮我们 千谢万谢
Thank you so much for doing this. Thank you. Thank you.
-别客气 -好 表演会6点开始
- Of course. - Okay, so her recital's at 6:00.
-好 -这是地址和她的演出服
- Okay. - That's the address. Here's her outfit.
这是我们的摄像机
This is our camcorder.
麻烦录下整场演出 还有幕后花絮
Get the whole show and some backstage color.
各位 要带上熟食拼盘在路上吃吗
Guys, you wanna take our charcuterie for the road?
不不不不 他们不用 我们自己吃吧
Bup, bup, bup, bup. They're good. We may need that.
喂
Hello?
是的
Yeah, um...
请稍等
H-hold on one second.
应该是宝宝的家人 他们在说西班牙语
I think it's the baby's family. They're speaking Spanish. I--
你好 我是卡梅隆 有事吗
HOLA, SOY CAMERON. OMO ESTA?
不好意思 麻烦你
Uh, b--excuse me. Could you s--
麻烦你说慢点
Could you slow down just a little bit?
"疯男迭戈"是什么意思
What does frenetico mean?
-就是 -让她接电话好了
- It's when... - Or just let her do it.
-就这样 你来讲 -喂
- Yeah. There you go. Okay. - Hello?
是 是
Si, si.
我说得好好的
I was doing fine.
他以为自己是个专家了
He thinks he's some sort of an expert
就因为这两周来 他一直在看
because for the past two weeks, he's been watching
一部荒诞的西班牙语肥皂剧
this ridiculous Spanish soap opera.
《水生火热》吗
"Fire and ice"?
千万别把昨晚的大结局剧透了
Don't say a word about the ending of last night's episode.
歌洛莉亚看那剧 剧透就全毁了
G-gloria watches that. You'll ruin it.
好的好的 谢谢
Si. Muchisimas gracias.
是孩子的姨妈 胡安妮塔
It was the mother's sister Juanita.
她说她还不知道是哪所医院
She said that she doesn't know the exact hospital yet,
但是她大概一小时后会再打给你
but that she will call you, like, in the next hour.
谢谢 歌洛莉亚 我想麻烦你帮个忙
Oh, thank you, Gloria. I-I hate to ask this of you,
你能和我们一起去吗
but would you mind coming with us?
我们需要个真正会说西班牙语的人
We need someone who actually knows how to speak Spanish.
我的心拔凉拔凉的
Frio. Muy frio.
好啊 当然可以啦 谢谢 谢谢
Ay, yes, of course! I would love to! Thank you! Thank you!
我这就去收拾东西 然后就出发 好吗
I'm gonna grab my stuff, and we go, okay?
好了 宝贝 快过来
All right, sweetheart. All right, come here.
爸爸要出发了
Daddies gotta go, okay?
宝贝 抱歉不能看你表演了
Okay, we're so sorry we're missing your recital, sweetie.
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
你马上就会多个刚出生的弟弟啦
You're getting a brand-new baby brother!
快走吧 快走吧
Cam, come on. Come on.
好的 好的 深呼吸 深呼吸
Okay. All right, breathe, breathe, breathe.
再见杰 再见曼尼 回头见啦
Ciao, Jay! Ciao, Manny! I see you later, okay?
这是怎么一回事
What just happened here?
我要上厕所
I have to go to the bathroom.
-她是跟你说话 -要不你来管吧
- She's talking to you. - You wanna take that?
首先脚步一定要跟上节奏
Always keep the rhythm in your feet.
然后肩膀上再加点花活 懂吗
Then we're gonna add just a little party in the shoulders. All right?
再来点手臂动作
Now let's get those arms going.
不 不 不 手放下面是在说
No, no, no. Arms down here says,
"哥是白人 对不起"
"I'm white and I'm sorry,"
但手举起来是表示
But arms up here says,
"哥很神秘 猜不透"
"You don't know what I am."
的确猜不透
I-I don't.
你们不会相信的
You're never gonna believe it!
猜猜谁找到工作了 是我
Guess who got a job! I did!
哎呀 包袱抖早了
Oh, shoot. I just told you.
-亲爱的 恭喜你 -太棒了
- Oh! Honey, congratulations! - That's amazing!
你找到工作了
You got a job!
这是些什么
And what is all this?
我路过杂货店 就买了点菜做晚饭
I stopped by the grocery store to get some stuff for dinner.
你知道杂货店在哪儿吗
You know where the grocery store is?
我知道 老妈
Yes, mother.
我今晚要为自己和迪兰做顿晚饭 以表庆祝
I'm celebrating by making dinner for me and Dylan tonight.
你和老爸要一起吗
Would you and dad like to join us?
-这是怎么回事 -不知道
- What's happening? - I don't know.
今晚吃晚饭时
Tonight at dinner,
我要告诉爸妈一个爆炸性的消息
I'm telling my parents the biggest news of all.
毕业之后 我要搬出去和某人同居
After graduation, I'm moving in with someone.
那个人 就是我
And his name is me.
看我跳舞
Watch me dance.
宝贝 你不必再练习了
Honey, you don't need to practice anymore.
旋转 跳跃 小鸟飞天状什么的
The turning, the jumping, the little bird thing--
你都练熟了
You've got it.
这是什么
What's this?
宝贝 请你不要动这些零件
Sweetie, please don't play with the pieces.
跟你说过了 它们脆弱得很
I've told you, they're very delicate.
你们在造什么
What are you building?
造飞机模型 著名女飞行家艾米莉亚的座驾
It's a model of a plane that was built for amelia earhart.
为什么
Why?
因为她想飞遍整个世界
Because she wanted to fly around the world.
为什么
Why?
也许她是给家里的娃整疯了
Because she probably needed to get away from her kids.
-为什么 -小哥来想个招
- Why? - You know how to stop this?
看我的
I'm on it.
莉莉 请你让我们专心工作
Lily, we really need you to let us concentrate
就一会儿 好吗
for a few minutes, okay?
你的发型真奇怪
Your hair is weird.
这回我没辙了
Um, now I'm flustered.
你真可爱
Oh, you look adorable!
"可爱" 我又不是小狗
"Adorable"? I'm not a puppy.
宝贝 我是在赞美你
Oh, honey, it was meant as a compliment.
克莱尔 看我的 宝贝 你真性感
Claire, I got this. Honey, you look super sexy.
真恶心
Ew.
好吧 这妞是两头堵啊
Well, we tried everything.
拜拜啦
Oh, good-bye!
等等 等等
Wait! Wait, wait!
让我们见见这翩翩公子嘛
We wanna meet this casanova.
别了 见父母这事还是饶了他吧
Oh, no, parents aren't really his scene.
艾利克斯 快开门 我们要给你俩照张相
Alex, open the door. We are going to get a picture.
好吧
Fine.
你 真是 完美无暇
You... look... flawless.
谢谢
Thanks.
我没说错吧 珊瑚色很适合你
Did I not say coral was the color for you?
跟你的肤色很搭啊
Look what it does for your skin.
-嗨 -嗨 小弟
- Hi! - Hi, buddy.
嗨
Hi.
好吧 我毕业舞会的男伴是个基佬
Yes, my bad boy prom date is gay.
只是他自己还蒙在"柜"里呢
He just doesn't know it yet,
我基本上只是他的"幌子"
so I'm basically his beard.
"幌子"的前帘
Pre-beard.
"幌子"上那一撮毛
His stubble.
好啦 喊"茄子"
Okay, say "Cheese"!
茄子
Cheese.
好 开闪光再来张
Okay, now one with flash.
-茄子 -茄子
- Cheese. - Cheese!
行了 照片你们该拍够了吧
Okay, I think you got the picture.
你们开开心心去玩吧
Well, you guys have fun.
亲爱的 要我帮你把头发整理一下吗
Do you want me to touch up your hair, honey?
不用了 没关系
Oh, no, I'm good.
开车别总左摇右摆跟蛇似的
Ay, please stop driving the car like a snake.
搞得我直犯恶心
It's making me nauseating.
你要是想换个地儿可以来后面
Well, uh, if you want to switch places,
后面地方足够大 你也好伸展得开
there's plenty of room to stretch out back here.
所以我们才把
Yeah, that's why we traded
以前的普锐斯换成现在这辆
our old Prius in for the new one.
你知道的 更多成员 更多空间
You know, bigger family, bigger backseat.
后面都能放下两个安全座椅
You can fit two car seats
外加一头足以得奖的肥猪了
and a prize-winning pig back there.
能不把我们的孩子和猪一起放后座上吗
Please don't put a pig in the backseat with our children.
我就是打个比方
I'm not being literal.
这不过是我们农场上的计量方法
It's a unit of measurement we used on the farm.
比如 这张床是"两头猪"的大小
You know, like, "That bed's a double-pigger."
不好意思 要不想点儿别的
Oh, uh, sorry. Maybe think about something else.
你看 我星期一没看到《水生火热》
You know, I missed "Fire and Ice" on Monday.
演了些什么
What happened?
我猜是一群极其养眼的神经质演员
My guess is a bunch of ridiculous plot turns
共同演绎了一段荒诞离奇的故事情节
done by overwrought actors who are impossibly good-looking.
-别听他胡说 -没关系 真的
- Don't listen to him. - Nothing, really.
安东尼奥雇了个妓女和他老爹结婚
Antonio hired a hooker to marry his father
这样他就能把钱夺回去了
so that he can get back the money,
结果发现那个妓女是他失散多年的妹妹
but the hooker ended up being his long lost sister,
那个前选美皇后
the former beauty queen.
看来我没猜错啊
Oh. Well, I stand uncorrected.
开车你就开得直一点行不
Ay, please just drive straighter.
对不起 我又翘兰花指了吗
Oh, sorry. Are my pinkies up again?
我激动的时候就会这样
I--they do that when I get excited.
下去 姐妹们
Down, girls!
艾丽克斯现在应该在跳舞了
Well, Alex should be hitting the dance floor right about now.
肯定很开心
Must be fun.
真的 爸爸 别说了
Really, dad, let it go.
对不起 亲爱的
I'm sorry, sweetie.
只是你不去舞会我很难过
I'm just sad you're missing it.
我还清楚记着我参加毕业舞会那晚
I can still totally picture my prom night.
我的女伴是安吉拉·威尔金斯
My date was Angela Wilkins.
我爸爸扮成了豪车司机 操着英国口音
My dad dressed as a limo driver and spoke with a British accent.
我们到达的时候 他还大声通报
He even announced our arrival.
"菲廉·邓菲先生和威尔金斯夫人驾到"
"Sir Philliam Dunphy and the Lady Wilkins!"
所有的酷小子都和我们一起乐翻了
All the cool kids were totally laughing with us.
真高兴我们在那之后认识了
Oh, I'm just so glad we met after that.
-我也是 -没错
- Me, too. - Yeah.
知道后来的安吉拉怎么样了吗
Wonder what ever happened to Angela?
你不知道吗
You don't know?
我二十年没见过她了
I haven't seen her in over 20 years,
不过这才是毕业舞会的魅力所在
but that's what's special about prom.
无论如何
No matter what...
那晚永远是我和威尔金斯夫人共同的回忆
the Lady Wilkins and I will always have that night.
放下 放下 我们来
Oh, no, no, no! We got this.
我们来收拾
We'll clean.
你们来收拾
You're cleaning up?
今天是什么日子
What kind of day is this?
小卡和米奇有了新儿子
Cam and Mitch get a new son,
我们又得了新女儿
we get a new daughter.
伙计们 今晚很开心
That was really fun, you guys.
没错 下次去我们家聚
Yeah, and next time, we'll just do it at our place.
我去 提前说一声就好
I'm in. Just give me a heads-up.
"我们家" 什么意思
"Our place"? What? What?
那个
Um, well,
既然我现在有工作了
Since I have a job now
又打算去上社区大学
and I'm going to community college,
我和迪兰考虑呢
uh, Dylan and I were thinking that, you know,
一起租个房子什么的
we would get an apartment together.
-什么 -你们会做爱吗
- What? - Are you doing sex?
-行了 -卢克 你先出去一会儿
- Okay. - Luke, can we have a minute, please?
听着
Listen...
我知道你们不放心
I know that you're concerned,
不过我现在在设计T恤 会有大号的
but I'm designing t-shirts now, and they're gonna be huge.
还有中号和小号的
Also medium and small.
迪兰 我们想单独和海莉说会儿话
Dylan, would you excuse us for a moment so we can talk to Haley?
当然 你们在这聊 我回避就好
Sure, but you stay. I'll go.
你好 晚上好
Hi. Uh, uh, buenos noches.
我们想找... 会说英语吗
Uh, uh, we're looking for... uh, English?
胡安妮塔 我们要找胡安妮塔
Uh, well, Juanita. We're looking for juanita.
-你好 -你好
- Hola! - Hi.
是米奇尔和卡梅隆吗
Mitchell y cameron?
她说 你们好 是米奇和卡梅隆吗
Ah, she says, "Hello, Mitch and Cameron."
这我们听得懂
I think we got that.
是你们请我来的
Ay, you brought me here.
谢谢
Thank you...
这段你们也听懂了吗
Did you get that, too?
对 大部分听懂了
Yeah, a lot of it. Mm-hmm.
还是告诉我们吧
Just... just tell us.
宝宝半小时前出生了 很健康
The baby was born half-hour ago, that he's in perfect health.
他有六斤五两 头发浓密 褐色的眼睛
He was 7 pounds, 4 ounces, with thick hair and brown eyes.
太好了
That's so good!
胡安妮塔
Juanita!
歌洛莉亚 怎么了
Gloria, what's going on?
不知道 牧师有要事告诫
I don't know. The priest comes with great warning.
肯定没好事
That can't be good.
轻点 是关于祖母的 她病了
Shh! Something about the grandmother. She's sick.
不过现在好多了
But now she's better.
-现在她知道了 -知道什么
- And now she knows! - Knows what?
这是干嘛
What was that for?!
那个护士偷了她祖母的杏仁
The nurse stole her grandmother's almonds.
不是 那护士记恨于胡安妮塔
No, the nurse is mad at Juanita
因为她把这护士的爱人给抢走了
because Juanita stole her lover,
胡安妮塔又同时记恨于那个护士
and Juanita is mad at the nurse
因为这护士把她宝宝的事告诉了她祖母
because the nurse told the grandmother about the baby!
-我们的宝宝吗 -我们的宝宝吗
- Our baby? - Our baby?
既然都这么想 不如让我说出来吧
We're both thinking it. I'm just gonna say it.
莉莉的舞姿跟刚这水准可差着十万八千里呢
Lily's dance is not up to the standard of what we just saw.
我已经神游着 去打高尔夫了
In my head, I'm golfing right now.
普里契特先生 我是莉莉的舞蹈老师露西
Hi, Mr. Pritchett? I'm Lily's dance teacher Lucy.
我们遇到了点小麻烦
We have a little bit of an issue.
莉莉不想上台表演了
Lily doesn't want to perform.
这小家伙
Oh, the poor thing.
-你去牵莉莉 我去取车 -不不
- You get the kid, I'll get the car. - Oh, no.
能否顺利上台对她自尊心的建立很重要
It's really important for Lily's self-esteem that she go on.
我觉得你们谁应该去跟她谈谈
I think one of you should talk to her.
你知道她跳得很烂 是吧
You know she stinks, right?
所以我想应该你去
And I think it should be you.
莉莉
Lily.
你的老师说你不想上台了 是真的吗
Your teacher tells me you don't want to dance. Is that true?
可你在家练习的时候
But you were so good back at the house
跳的多好啊
when you were practicing.
我想回家 回我家
I wanna go home, to my house.
回你自己家
Ah, to your house, huh?
是因为爸爸们都不在而伤心了吗
Are you sad your dads aren't here?
是啊 他们也会因为错过这个而伤心
Yeah. Well, I know they're sad to miss this,
但他们去接你的小弟弟了
But they're getting you that baby brother.
这是好事 对吧
That's good, right?
你知道的 亲爱的
You know, honey,
你两个爸爸还是会一样爱你的
Your dads are gonna love you just as much
小弟弟来了也不会变 相信我
when you get this brother. Trust me.
我先有了你克莱尔姑姑 然后你爸出生了
I first had your Aunt Claire, and then your dad came along,
我对他们都的爱都一样深
and I loved them just the same,
虽然你爹可能不这么说
no matter what he tells you.
你相信我吗
You believe me?
这就够了
Close enough.
你说呢
So what do you say?
你会上去跳舞给大家看吗
You gonna go out there and dance for everybody?
不
No.
亲爱的 我总能干点什么让你上台的吧
Honey, there must be something I can do to get you out there.
来跟我一起跳 爷爷
Come dance with me, grandpa.
不 亲爱的 这是不可能滴
No, honey, that's not gonna happen.
我给你五十块钱咋样
How about I give you 50 bucks?
我不理解为什么我就不能这样做
I don't see why I can't do this.
我完全有能力掌控自己的人生
I'm totally getting my life together.
请允许我给你
Uh, allow me, if you will,
准确描绘一下你以为自己想要的生活
to paint an accurate picture of this life
是什么样的 好吗
Yeah. You think you want, okay?
起初 分分钟妙不可言
Um, at first, it's a blast--
去买个餐盘架
buying a dish rack,
挂个床单 把房间一分为二
hanging a sheet up to turn one room into two.
用通用扳手捣鼓出个"四不像"书柜
Allen-wrenching a bookcase called a nurnk...
因为你连宜家的组装货的买不起
because you couldn't afford the sklurg.
接下来呢
But then...
账单源源不断地涌进来
Then those bills start rolling in...
这样你就不得不多轮几班
Oh. So you gotta pick up some extra shifts.
对 然后猛不丁的
Yeah. And suddenly...
这是啥啊 你怀孕了
Uh-oh, what's that? You're pregnant.
早该注意的
Should've been safe.
弄得你焦头烂额 精疲力尽
Ooh, and you're stressed and exhausted.
车库里装满了卖不出去的T恤衫
You've got a garage filled with unsold huge t-shirts.
还有 亲爱的 如果你觉得这种压力
And, honey, if you think this kind of stress
还不足以对你的身材长相造成任何影响
is not gonna take its toll on that body and that face,
再想想吧
think again.
好皮肤只能再见
Good-bye, beautiful skin.
如丝般秀发也永别了
Farewell, silky hair.
就等着穿艾丽克斯给你的旧衣服吧
And hello, Alex's hand-me-downs,
因为商店里的你是买不起了
'cause you can't afford to shop.
这针见"血"了
Good one.
你觉得这行得通吗
Do you think that this is gonna work out?
能啊
Yes.
我说的是我爹妈那边
Well, for my parents, I mean.
至于你嘛
For you?
不能
No.
天呐
God.
我真的太想跟海莉一块生活了
I just wanna live with Haley so bad.
我在怀俄明那么长时间 没办法和她在一起
It's like, I missed all this time with her in Wyoming.
现在回来了她又要去上大学 我怕失去她
Then I thought I was gonna lose her again to college.
别担心 我罩着你 有我在就不可能
Don't worry. I got your back, buddy. That's not gonna happen.
你那是什么意思
What does that mean?
迪兰 把门关上
Dylan, shut the door.
卧室的门
The bedroom door.
抱歉 抱歉
Excuse me. Excuse me.
那个
Okay.
我们非常困惑
We're very confused.
能有人告诉我们到底发生什么事了吗
Can somebody please just tell us what's happening?
有人跟祖母说了宝宝的事
Somebody told the grandmother about the baby,
她本来不该知道的
and she wasn't supposed to know.
要我说 是那迷死人的神父说的
If you ask me, it was the sexy priest.
够了
Enough!
不是神父
It wasn't the priest.
是我
It was me.
爱德华多
Eduardo!
到底咋回事
What's happening?
是的 我还活着
Yes, I am alive.
没错 我是个放羊的
And I may be just a ranch hand,
但是我告诉了你祖母孩子的事
but I'm the one that told your abuela about the baby.
我告诉她是因为我向你母亲发过誓
I told her because I swore to your mother
要照顾你们家人
to look after your family.
你的母亲
Your mother...
是我的情人
was my lover.
等一下 我现在得把英文翻成成西语
Ay, wait a minute. Now I go from English to Spanish.
我们现在能见宝宝了吗
C-can we please just see our baby?
不能
No!
-祖母 -祖母
- Abuela? - Abuela?
她说她要抚养孩子长大
She's saying that she's going to raise the baby.
不是吧
No.
小卡
Cam.
过来 过来
Come here. Come on.
你猜怎么的 突然间你就已经六十岁了
Guess what? Suddenly, you're 60 years old,
牙都掉光了 在一块不毛之地上瞎晃悠
wandering toothless and alone in a postapocalyptic wasteland.
等一下 迪兰是怎么拿到核武器代码来着
Wait a second. How did Dylan get the nuclear codes again?
在机器人战争的时候
During the robot wars.
好了 我想你爸有点
Okay, I think your father might have gotten
扯太远了 亲爱的 重点是
a little bit off-track here. Honey, listen, the point is,
你今天所做的一切决定
The choices you make today--
不 重点是
No, no, the point is,
事情不一定非要向坏的方向发展
is that it doesn't have to turn out so bad.
她说的对
She's right.
不一定 卢克
It doesn't. Luke?
昨天寄来的
This came yesterday.
是什么
What is it?
是那大学寄来的
It's from that college.
你被录取了 海莉
You got in, Haley.
-迪... -我的天
- Oh, D-- - Oh, my god.
-你被大学录取了 -什么
- You got into college? - What?!
太好了
That's amazing!
是昨天寄来的
It came yest-- yesterday?
卢克 你为什么要藏起来
Luke, why were you hiding this?
不知道
I don't know.
你不想让她去上大学吗
Do you not want her to go to college?
我不关心
I don't care.
你会想我的
Aw! You're gonna miss me!
闭嘴 我才不会 再也不告诉你任何事了
Shut up! I am not! I'm never telling you anything again.
抱歉 小兄弟 但大学她还是得去上的
Sorry, little dude, but she's gotta go to college,
哪怕这意味着她不能和我同居
Even if that means that she can't live with me.
迪兰
Oh, Dylan.
不过你能答应我一件事吗
Could you do one thing for me, though?
能让我陪你去参加毕业舞会吗
Could you take me to your prom?
-你真的想吗 -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
如果你去上大学 不再回来了
I mean, if you go off to college and you don't come back here,
我希望你能记住我
I want you to remember me.
我要做你的安吉拉·威尔金斯
I wanna be your Angela Wilkins.
-妈 -什么事
- Mom? - Yes.
我说你老得不能穿的那条紫色裙子
Can I borrow that purple dress I said you were
能借我吗
too old for?
你可真会借东西 好吧
Mm, in spite of that, yeah. Yeah.
邓先生
Mr. D.
你有没有礼服可以借我的
Do you have a tuxedo I could borrow?
当然有 这可是我的结婚礼服
Yeah, sure. I mean, it's the tux I got married in,
是双排扣的[两块胸肌]
So it's double-breasted.
太好了 我也是
Perfect. So am I.
好吧
Okay.
我去买点吃的垫垫肚子
I'm going to get something for my stomach.
快刷呀
Oh, come on, swipe.
刷呀
Swipe!
米奇尔 来帮我一下
M-mitchell, I need your help.
刷不了 我现在也没心情"找收银员"
It won't swipe, and I'm in no condition to "See cashier."
米奇尔
Mitchell.
Mitchell?
米奇 米奇尔 你去哪里啊
Mitch--Mitchell! Where are you going?!
我受够了 小卡
I'm just sick of it, Cam.
米奇尔 回来我们聊聊
Mitchell, come back here and talk to me.
这里有土狼 还有吸毒的
There are coyotes out here and--and meth addicts!
小卡 每一次
Every time, Cam.
每一次有人说我们能领养个孩子
Every time someone says that we're getting a-a baby,
我都寄以希望
I get my hopes up and then...
却总是以失望而告终 我...
And then when it all falls apart, I...
我们又得从头到尾再经历一遍
We just have to go through the whole thing again.
但同时 我们已经拥有的孩子
And then meanwhile, the child that we do have
正在演出 但我们却错过了
is--is at a recital, and--and we're missing it.
我知道
I know.
我和你一样沮丧
I'm as frustrated as you are.
是吗 因为我不
Are you? Because I-I don't--
我不知道我还能承受多少次
I don't know how much more of this I can take.
我心力憔悴
I am--I am so tired
失望透顶
and--and just disappointed.
累到无以复加
And... I'm just tired.
那我们缓缓吧
Then let's take a break.
真的吗
Really?
我们俩一直这样撑着
It must be exhausting,
肯定已经精疲力竭了
always keeping it together for the both of us.
我也累了
And I'm tired, too.
我觉得我躺在块石头上了
I think I'm lying on a rock.
我躺在我的"磐石"旁边
I'm lying next to my rock.
人一辈子 有些时刻是永远无法忘怀的
There's certain moments in life that you never forget,
比如说我第一次将曼尼拥入怀中
Like when I held Manny in my arms for the very first time.
我很紧张 我不知所措
I was nervous. I didn't know what I was doing.
怎么样
What do you think?
-俊男靓女啊 -我们的宝贝女儿
- You guys look amazing. - Oh, our little girl!
看到他的成长让我兴奋不已
And I was excited to see him grow up.
-拜拜 宝贝 -玩得开心
- Bye, sweetie. - Have fun, man.
她睡着了
She's asleep.
跟你说孩子 我老得没法当爹了
I tell you, kid, I'm too old for this.
我们都是
You and me both.
随着他慢慢成长为今天的小大人模样
And the more he becomes the little man I know today,
我越来越意识到自己愿意重来一次
the more I know I would do it all over again...
正好 因为我真的要重来一次
Which is good, because I'm going to do it all over again.
原来我不是晕车
Turns out that I wasn't carsick.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
卢克
Okay, Luke,
-看看你还藏了些什么 -好吧
- Let's see what else you've been hiding from us. - Okay, fine.
这是我在牧场炸掉的鸟窝的罚单
Here's a bill for the birdhouse I blew up at the dude ranch.
你炸了个鸟窝
You blew up a birdhouse?
说完了再一起问吧
Let's hold all questions until the end.
这是我们去迪士尼那天
Here's dad's jury duty thing
通知老爸做陪审员的
for the day we went to disneyland.
我不想让你们取消行程
I didn't want you to cancel the trip.
做得好
Good call.
这是射击场给妈的优惠券
Here's a coupon for a gun range for mom.
我不知道是什么东西
I don't know what that's about.
我也不知道
I don't know either. It's...
成绩单
Report card.
市里寄来的拆掉树屋的通知
Notice from the city to take down the tree house
否则每天罚款25块
or be fined $25 a day...
成绩单
Report card.
闯红灯罚单 那次我和曼尼偷...
Red light ticket for when me and Manny stole that...